Jérémy MARTIN

CLINICAL BIOINFORMATICIAN

@martin-jeremy
 in @jeremy-martin-tlse
 R⁶ @Jeremy-Martin-20

Formerly a medical laboratory technician, I became a bioinformatics engineer. I have experience in R/Python scripting and R Shiny development. I have also been able to conduct analyses on bulk/scRNA seq and microarray transcriptomic data.

jeremy.delpech.martin@gmail.com

30 B CHEMIN SANSOU, 31500 TOULOUSE

29 years old

Driving licence (B)
Driving licence (A)

06 50 20 77 61

Open to remote work

Bio-informatics Skills

Linux / Bash

R/RStudio

R Shiny

Python

Transcriptomics (sc/RNA seq)

Hi-C

Clinical Biology Skills

Microbiology

Biochemistry

Immunology

Haemostatis

Haematology

Languages

Spanish

B2/C1.

English

B1/B2.

Travel

Amérique du Sud Road-trip au Pérou et en Equateur durant l'été 2018.

Europe Espagne (Palma de Majorque, Madrid, Barcelone, Alicante, Valence), Hongrie (Budapest), Portugal (Lisbonne).

Education

09/2019 - 06/2021

MASTER de Bioinformatique et Biologie des Systèmes

Université Paul Sabatier TOULOUSE

Master of Bioinformatics. Theoretical and practical training allowing the acquisition of multidisciplinary skills in Biology, Computer Science, Bioanalysis and Mathematics necessary to meet the needs in this field. Tutored project: Benchmarking of read counting tools and characterization of a difference in the calculation of the sequencing

09/2017 - 06/2019

LICENCE de Biochimie, Biologie Moléculaire et Microbiologie

Université Paul Sabatier TOULOUSE

Bachelor's degree in Biology with a focus on Biochemistry.

Theoretical and practical training in the techniques of Biochemistry,
Molecular Biology and Microbiology applied in the field of
Biotechnology.

Choice of optional courses: Plant Improvement, Professional Project, Advanced Immunology, Project Management.

09/2012 - 06/2014

BTS Analyses de Biologie Médicale

Lycée Dr LACROIX NARBONNE

Advanced Technician's Certificate. Theoretical and practical training in Biochemistry, Molecular Biology, Microbiology, Immunology and Hematology. Acquisition of laboratory techniques, awareness of quality, GBEA and ISO 15189.

Work experience in Bioinformatics

07/2021

Bioinformatics Engineer

INSERM - Institut Toulousain des Maladies Infectieuse et Inflammatoires TOULOUSE (31)

Temporary position within the N. GAUDENZIO research lab.

- Analysis of data generated by the lab.
- Summarise and presentation of results.
- Development of pipeline to automate analysis.
- Proof of concept in various techniques such as machine learning or multiplex imaging.
- Supervision of Master 2 interns as part of the laboratory's academic mission
- Professionnal watch.

06/2019 - 06/2021

Internship during MSc

INSERM / INRAE TOULOUSE (31)

INSERM - Institut Toulousain des maladies Infectieuses et Inflammatoires

6-Months Internship within the N. GAUDENZIO research lab.

- Development of an analysis pipeline for the lab.
- Analysis of scRNA seq data generated by the lab (immune cells, sensory neurons).
- Neuro-immune interactome study.
- Peptidomics and proteomics analysis.
- Integration of data from bulk, scRNAseq and microarray.

INRAE - UMR GENPHYSE

2-Months Internship with T. FARRAUT.

- Development of a pipeline to deals with Hi-C data.
- Obtaintion of a chromosomic map of a region of interest.
- Wrap the pipeline into a Snakemake workflow for reproductibility.

Work epxperience in Clinical Laboratory

02/2016 - 09/2017

Technicien polyvalent de laboratoire

Labosud / INOVIE Toulouse

CDI. Polyvalent technician:

- Attached to the HEMATO division: hematology, immunohematology, hemostasis.
- In charge of the formation of the new arrivals on the pole HEMATO.
- Realization of the usual routine in biochemistry, microbiology.
- Realization of 'small manual techniques' in immunology and serology.

09/2015 - 02/2016

Technicien de Laboratoire Clinique

EFS, CEDIBIO, Proxilab31, Biofusion TOULOUSE (31)

Several temporary and fixed-term positions:

- Blood sampling in clinic and on peripheral sites.
- Multi-skilled technician on technical platform in hematology, immuno-hematology, microbiology and biochemistry.
- Handling of labile blood products and shipping to the French Laboratory of Fractionation and Biotechnology (LFB) for the preparation of blood-derived drugs.

07/2014 - 08/2015

Technicien de Laboratoire

IUCT Oncopôle TOULOUSE (31)

CDD. Clinical Anatomical Cytopathology Technician:

- Trained in the standard management of histological specimens (description, dehydration, inclusion, sectioning, staining, immunohistochemistry).
- Specialized in pathological cytology.
- Participated in the implementation of quality in the cytologypathology department of Pr COURTADE-SAÏDI, according to ISO-15189 standard.